profiles in holography is brought to you
through the generous support of the
international holography fund for more
information visit their website at
holographyfund.org
hello everyone this is Frank de Freitas
and I would like to welcome you to
another installment of holotalk my guest
for this broadcast is Stephen Smith of
lasersmith now the show is a little bit
over 30 minutes long so instead of me
giving you the introduction I'm going to
take you over there and let Steve do it
for himself he gives a wonderful
description of his past history and
holography and his thoughts about
holography in general and the future so
without further Ado here's Stephen Smith
on holotalk
Hello Steven how are you it's Frankie
Freitas
Frank how are you doing good I want to
welcome you to the show I've always
wanted to speak to you but I've never
had the opportunity for the two of us to
mean I know you have a rich history in
holography you also have the luckiest
name in holography I can't think of any
other name that would go after laser
that would fit as well as lasersmith
you know and I have to give a really
good friend of mine from the early days
I was in Chicago back in the early 70s
with coming up with that name because I
was uh running around with some
Holograms and my middle initial is L and
he just started saying oh it's that
lasersmith guy oh and that was uh kind
of funny that was really so it was like
a no-brainer after uh what started out
as a snide remark ended up being
something I'm quite proud to play around
with but you know why I really liked it
too
because the village Smithy he was or she
was you know how you look at this thing
in history that Artisan in the village
that made stuff yes exactly and for me
that was so much what holography was
about you and those early days you were
like taking these materials and trying
to Smith them into a hologram
two of them as it be but anyway yeah
yeah why don't you start off by telling
the listeners a little bit about your
early history and I imagine that was in
the Chicago area
well yeah let's let's look at it that
way I got my Bachelor of Science degree
from Southern Illinois University in
Carbondale
and in between my junior year and my
senior year I took a year off what I
thought was going to be a year off went
up to Chicago and worked got a job in
the photo industry doing a lot of um
photo compose
you know the kind of Photography work
that you did at advertising agencies
science yeah like pre-press color
separating things color preparation
um where you're doing what would be
considered posterized color you know
doing a lot of work with different
codoliths so you can you know comp
pictures inside of other pictures Okay
so this turned out to be really
fundamentally helpful a few years later
I went back I saw my first hologram
at a school of the Art Institute
media and new technology show that was a
number of grad students had put together
and believe it or not there was a
hologram in there from Dr Jiang oh what
year was that this was like something
like 76 and this is a hologram that was
a little car I think it was called quick
turnaround okay
and it was a little circular hologram oh
that was that was one of his first uh
360 laser transmission cylinder
Holograms yeah
and I was very captured by that at that
point in my career I was really kind of
a fine art photographer I had a 4x5 view
camera
I used to spend my off days sleeping
around Chicago
doing black and white and color work I
had my own diet transfer lab in my one
of my bedrooms in my apartment and I was
doing color separations and doing
um if your listeners are familiar with a
photographer by the name of George Tice
it's kind of like Urban landscape
photography okay and that's what I was
doing in 75 and 74.
and then I saw this hologram and as an
image maker in photography I was very
much about a printmaker I really cared a
lot about the quality of the print that
was a part of the process that
communicated my vision or image
through to the viewer and I was very
much an art photographer
and so
um I called my old instructor Chuck
swedland down at Southern Illinois and I
said you know I want to come back and
finish up my senior year and I've caught
wind of this new thing called holography
and I want to know if you might let me
spin that up into my senior thesis so he
checked around campus he gave me the
name of a professor a Dr zitter Who is
over in the physics department that's an
and Dr zitter had a helium neon laser so
they said you know what we can make this
work come on back so I went back down in
77.78 to finish my senior year and did
kind of a mix of holography
and photography
and I need to put something in here real
important after I saw my first hologram
and found out that it was made by a
physics Professor up in Lake Forest just
north of Chicago I went and signed up
for his summer holography workshops oh
okay and took two of them and at that
that really it was like
people were getting frustrated with me
because all I ever talked about was
holography and trying to get a laser you
were called to do this it was just yeah
it's like that little mouse or a little
squirrel that sees a shiny thing needs
to collect it something happened I was
just this I have to know how to do this
because to me it was an extension of the
image now it was the ultimate
printmaking I wasn't dealing with dyes
or silver anymore on a paper I was able
to make structures that diffracted light
so the color in my photographs could be
light
that's that's what appealed to me that's
what got my
my dander up as they say and where did
you go after that well I came back and
uh again went back to work at the same
company they were actually kind of
pleased that I came back in
uh a place called gamma photo and I had
the job of the as a manager of the
duplication Department which was like an
extension the stuff I'd been doing
but then I started pestering them I
started showing them my Holograms that I
was making in my own little five
milliwatt laser in what at the time when
I moved back I moved down into the
Western section of the Chicago Loop
where the old vegetable markets used to
be near Fulton Street I had a loft
photography studio I was still doing
photography on the side but I had to
support myself so I had a full-time job
as the manager of this color dupe
department and I'd bring him in my
Holograms and I'd show them and I'd say
you know these are really really getting
kind of interesting to do what do you
think and they kind of were like you
know we're we don't see this being
interesting it's not something and they
gotten I got in trouble with the
management
so I at that point was interested in
doing holography full time and was
trying to figure out a way to do it so I
looked for another another photo lab
that they had opening on the night shift
so I could work from five in the evening
until one in the morning and then I had
days to work in my little lab
and took that job over at kns
photographics so now we're talking
and at the same time was had built up my
little lab was doing Holograms with a
little uh 2.5 or 5 milliwatt Heaney
did your investment back then at five
million that was like serious money it's
like more than two thousand dollars it
certainly was and uh and it was like and
it was such a pitiful amount of light
and I was making a little tiny like one
inch in diameter and reflection
Holograms that you could like barely see
because nobody had really heard about
pyracom yeah okay so we were doing all
this
you know really heavily silver Laden
Holograms that were fixed and because of
the um you know they're shot in red but
there was all the silver in them and
collapsing and so they were green you
were probably working with the Mercure
chloride and some of those other
chemicals yeah good stuff and here's
where the nice another little fun caveat
happens I'm going to have a lot of
friends in my building that are students
at the school of the Art Institute and
I'm going to all the you know weekends
going to parties a different students
house and uh I'm at a party one evening
and I'm
talking to a woman who's there girl
trying to make conversation and at one
point she's got frustrated said you know
there's another guy here who's trying to
talk to me about the same stuff this is
holography stuff I'm going to introduce
you to him you want to talk to somebody
about this go talk to him and he
introduced me to Tom svetkovic oh yes
yes and so uh in meeting Tom I found out
there was somebody else that was like
really keenly interested in holography
and he was doing some Consulting with
zenith
so that kind of Spun so in the Summers
I'm doing like workshops and holography
at Lake Forest in the daytime Tom and I
are kind of talking about how can we
make Holograms work
and we started we figured well one thing
we can do is this is obviously more
money than either one of us have why
don't we try to do this thing there was
a young man a guy in Chicago who had
started a thing called a Cooperative
dark room where people could rent time
on enlargers who didn't you know have a
dark room I thought why couldn't we do
something like that for holography why
don't we have like a Cooperative
holography lab and that began the
Chicago holographic Cooperative oh I
have never heard of that connections
myself Tom some students uh people uh
Victor Heredia
um Rick Brock Melissa Crenshaw a whole
group of people that have been taking
holography classes up at Lake Forest and
also at the 1134 gallery of holography
in Washington Street in Chicago we're
all actually kind of Milling around
Chicago looking for like how can we do
this
so we started meeting at my studio at
952 West Lake Street and it's a
photography studio and I have my little
holography lab there that really wasn't
much but I was able to do some things
and we would have monthly meetings what
are you doing bringing Holograms talk
about Holograms who wants to start a lab
um
you know Tom had a laser had some
equipment and we ended up meeting a
woman that owned an Old Firehouse a
couple blocks from me at 114 North
Aberdeen
and she was like I've got a tenant on
the first floor he's got a meat packing
company got these trucks with smelly
meat in there I'd be glad to rent you
the first floor do whatever you want
so Tom and I took out a lease
one year lease took up took the
bit up to start with
and built our first table
started putting the table together now
we're talking this night late 97 79 and
going into the spring of 1980 and we had
the first table up the dark room
processing was happening and he and I
had built had been making you know he
had a bigger laser yay red laser yep
and there we were we were making four by
five Holograms I think that's right
around the time of the first Workshop of
the whole Symposium on holography okay
that would be 82
. okay so right around 82.
paper by lawnmower color control oh yes
and holography yes Tom and I were like
oh this is going to be hot right away
ran back to the lab started playing
around with processing and the color
control which is p benzoquinone which is
another really bad leech it didn't
really want to be messing with
anything comes in a package that's a
cardboard box inside of that is a a
aluminum foil cellophane bag that's been
vacuum sealed
which inside of that is another glass
container inside of that is another
container it's like in a skull and
crossbones on the front yeah so
p-benzoquinone from the holographer
that was in your uh
pseudocolor Holograms right that's when
we started doing pseudocolor Holograms
and uh up at that point we were meeting
every day at the little holography lab
in the back of this Firehouse
making Holograms some single color some
transmission trying to put together what
would be the equivalent of a portfolio I
knew some art directors at a number of
different agencies around Chicago I had
a couple of really good friends who were
also
um
photographers that were doing commercial
photography work and they were putting
me touch with people and we put together
three color control Holograms and went
into an advertising agency that was um
called Franklin company
what Holograms were they there was a
Holograms two Holograms of little shells
I had found on the beach of crabs
so this crab shell that was green and a
crab shell that was gold
floating through the surface of the
plate
and we met with a guy art director whose
name was Bill takazuki and at the time
he had a big client called McDonald's
and they were doing point of sale
signage for McDonald's oh he said you
know what this is like really really
cool stuff
he said if you had more equipment could
you make these bigger and could you do
these better because he said because
nobody's ever come in here and showed me
Holograms it could be this is that color
and this is that color
so Tom and I came back we set up their
little exhibition room with the 12
different Holograms two were laser lit a
couple were
reading that built the case the case was
like took two people to carry it up all
made out of wood all those little slots
for the whole grams were set in the
laser to set in and the whole thing set
it up
they brought in a number of different
accounting sects that was there for
about a four hour period we hung around
and answered questions while people
there then a guy came there who was the
account exec for McDonald's
and he said we're going to have a
meeting leave all this stuff here I want
you here tomorrow morning at nine
o'clock
came in the next morning at nine met the
head buyer from the McDonald's
corporation
spent all day at the agency talking
about ideas
at the end of that day we walked out
with a contract to do a holographic art
piece for McDonald's new school campus
wow that was a notebook it wasn't a lot
of money said look we can't bankroll you
but if you do stuff for us and we build
the program we'll make this happen
so with that a happy day huh that was a
happy day that was a day that was the
day we called up coherent and convinced
them that they needed to sell us a
five watt Krypton laser
which was interesting that's the whole
story itself convincing like you guys
are who and you're going to do what and
uh but they did well isn't that nice
so we did and that's what I went that
very next day to my job and said uh you
know you're right I've got to do this
holography thing so I let I
went full time and from that day forward
there was never a day we were not busy
doing holograms for something well isn't
that something
and you have a number of patents to your
dwell uh through the work that developed
um with
um you know there's such a thread
because a lot of early work was
reflection Holograms and then we got
involved in doing photoresist and
photoresist led to mass replication and
mass replication led to
baseball cards and baseball cards led to
the multiple camera system yeah are you
involved with the security Holograms as
well well we were for a while for a
while but you have to in realizing that
part of my thread that was the
photographer I was very much interested
in holography as that next step forward
in image making
you know and that that's a big open
canvas to paint on it could still work
it could be you know that that hybrid
between video and still I mean that's
what holography so phenomenal it's
really a four-dimensional tool in many
ways
what does holography do that gives us
ability to say that it's the next step
in imaging what is that next step
I feel it still has not given us its
full potential it has not
through many of the reasons are Hardware
related you know resolution coming up
with devices that can have the
resolution you need for holographic
Imaging but it's getting there
real-time updateable 3D displays I mean
if there's one thing that a hologram can
do that
other types of stereoscopic media cannot
do
and that is a
correctly rendered three-dimensional
scene where convergence and focus are
correct okay
okay and and that to me and then when
you tie to that renewable whatever 60
frames a second
it becomes that phenomenal visual
interface I mean our eyes are the most
developed tool set of our whole body
we do so much processing just by looking
at something
I remember seeing seeing you at not I
wasn't there myself but I remember
seeing a photo of you
with a long Bank of individual cameras
so that you could do portraiture without
having any amount of time passing would
just be one exposure
multiple camera is that you yes what's
the story have you did you follow
through with that that was that did a
lot of work with that for a while that
was the 36 camera multi-camera system
and the the impetus for doing that was
having done what was the equivalent of
like still life
photography you know objects on a table
lit you know we were beginning to bump
our heads against the boundary of well
could you do something that's a real
thing
and so you know we already had a really
good contract going with upper deck and
so we were you know
Smith inspectovic holography had had
ended and Tom and I'd splitted
directions and the Ladysmith came into
being and within that period of time of
the lasersmith we got heavily involved
in trying to break that other boundary
get holography able to deliver to
whoever was interested in it besides the
artist and a commercial side
um images of the kind of things they
could go to a photographer and get real
life yeah yeah and so this became kind
of an outlandish idea in one sense I
mean sure I've got a really rich
photography history I know about my
bridge multiple camera system you know
Imaging sequences of images to kind of
like dissect motion
and there had been people that had built
multiple camera systems to do stereo
photography
nobody had ever taken the challenge with
the new cameras the available the
electronic shutter control that was now
available and specifically to angle you
know deal with them relative to the
holographic image problem so
sitting down doing a quick calculation I
you know worked out
basically if I took the seven to nine
millimeters that you might consider to
be that active area behind your pupil
that's your retina that when you're
looking at something at M's length how
many different views do I need to have
to kind of fill that out 15 inches wide
that's where the number 36 came from oh
I see so
um
put together a small group of you know
my lasersmith was half of the funds
Gary Zucker will be the marketing guy
who put together the upper deck deal put
together another quarter and Dr Jung
also a coupled in and we formed a group
called advanced advanced holographic
imaging technology a hit
and that was specifically to do image
capture initially for sports cards for
upper deck that's
yes very nice
the upper deck
people that still ask questions about
the upper deck and maybe you can
sort of clarify a few things on that
footage
that someone sees in one of the Upper
Deck cards that provide
several seconds about
yeah but you gotta be careful of which
ones because there is a group of them
that I did with this camera system and
then there are later ones
that were done which would just be like
a
very high number multi-channel hologram
had nothing stereo to do about it so
there's I want to be real clear there's
later Holograms that have been done for
upper deck that I've got nothing to do
with the multiple cameras
they're just taking you know 25 or 30
frames of video footage and
Imaging them sequentially like you would
yes in a stereogram except they don't
have any three-dimensional data yes
and they'll do some tracking because
they got to get rid of any camera Jitter
or blur they might even you know stay
relatively positioned with the the
carrier of the ball or the guy hitting
them you know whatever so but that's
different that's not the multiple camera
system there was only
one set of hockey cards done with the
multiple camera system
so Mark matier breath Hall
one other really great hockey guy were
they more less static images no they
were they were emotions where there was
an interesting problem this is where I
was kind of pushing enable up too much
these have motion I've got one where
Mark Messier and Brett Hull are fighting
for the puck oh so as you move the
Hologram back and forth not only are
they 3D and skating at you but their
sticks are also going back and forth
I've got another one where I'm talking
about and I'm sitting here grasping for
the guy's name he was uh with he was
from Canada originally but he was a big
big name player for the California
Los Angeles team I can't remember his
name but he does what he really he
smacks the puck and it's reminiscent of
that strobe photograph of the guy
swinging the tennis racket and hitting
the ball okay okay in the sense that
every single
sectional sweep of that pot of the
hockey stick up till the point where it
hits the park and the puck speeds away
is is there but it's there
three-dimensionally as well as
sequentially okay
that's interesting because there were a
few of us trying to determine
whether we were actually seeing any
dimensional properties to some of those
cards that were produced
for a national chain I think it was
Denny's or something right all of that
you know I did a bunch of those for
American banknote but they were not done
with the multiple camera system as hard
as a but there is dimensional properties
are we all
mistaken those were rethink because I
think I overspoke on top of what you're
saying I'm sorry
the those cars that we're speaking of
the the
produced the American banknote but not
with the multiple camera system
are we correct in seeing dimensional
properties to those cards they're not I
would say you're just kind of visually
thinking you're saying thinking they're
seeing it okay it's a single camera yes
sequence of time yeah
some of them were baseball
we were with Ken dunkley
an early holographer I know him yes and
he has a system where you can see
three-dimensional from one perspective
do with a
small pinhole and Iris
a viewer that you use just with magazine
for
photos wind up being
on view mastery
Master completely go 3D but you're just
hook that out sometime send me a link if
there's any yes I will I will do that it
really makes your hair stand up on
something to sing so I was wondering if
the same type of thing might have been
happening with those cards because we
passed a few of those around over the
summer
and some of us said there is most
definitely demand going on here well and
everybody was saying well how could
there be it's only one perspective but
if there is let's say if the motion
that's been captured like I became
really aware of this with a multiple
camera system I had to make sure that
people moved spun or directed their
emotion in particular directions okay if
they moved counterclockwise which was
the cameras triggered from left to right
because I kind of thought like you know
not you know
kind of Western reading English learning
style we read from right yes yes so my
Holograms are made
tip them from the left to the right so
your right eye is always advanced in
time from your left eye
say a person moves the wrong direction
if they move
right let's see stage I think stays up
so I gotta turn around they move
right to left yeah so they're keeping
position with the tracking of the
cameras
there's no stereoscopic correct data
and so they become flattened or if they
move too fast they actually invert so I
have an image of a peacock dancer where
her hand moves the wrong way and it
looks like it's going back through her
back
same thing could be said of these motion
images
if there is some motion and it's the
motion sequentially from the you know
they are also recorded in time left to
right
so at the latter time if the baseball
player let's say he's hitting the ball
and sequentially the bat has come around
so you're seeing the bat to the right
and the um the right eye but it's to the
left and the left eye because it hadn't
quite gotten to that position
you're going to perceive that as being a
stereoscopic data I see his body will
look 2D because it didn't move much or
it might have rotated the same way and
it might look a little bit yes but
that's how I think you're getting those
they'd be like false depth wonderful I
believe that would explain things and
we'll have to take a second look at them
no to
as we move
forth rotate them and
the directions and see if that
dimensional effect
appears
yes yeah I think that's worth looking at
politics and I'm very do forward me his
little pinhole 3D
definitely anything through them very
I'm getting very interested in 3D again
it kind of had kind of evolved away from
it after having left the media lab
I will have to check around here because
I S I had one of his units
and I think I may know where it's at
because I loaned it to somebody they did
send
put it in store
I will get that out and if you forward
to me your address I'll send you one of
the units to take a look at and try out
oh I'll be glad to do that I think you
would enjoy that and I hope it works for
you it doesn't work for everyone the
person I send it to said
I did immediately and I swear the hair
on my arms stood up straight it was just
sore
there's no information
it's a photograph in a magazine
but if you're looking at I mean the
mountains are off in the distance the
trees come towards you
you'll see maybe it'll work okay
definitely have to look at that okay so
what's what are your plans for the
future now
now oh I don't know what your age is but
I guess you have to be thinking about
retirement sometime in the future but
it's a retirement but before that what
would you like to do and still achieve
well I'm I'm seeing things get very
interesting again in this kind of hybrid
area of digital holography
um and having worked with Steve Benton
uh the seven years I was at the almost
eight years at the media lab
and some of the side work I mean mostly
my work was with the holographic printer
and auto stereoscopic displays
but I from time to time would get
involved in the rendering Hardware side
of the Holo video system
and and real-time holographic displays
are an interesting phenomenon and with
the work that I did in the One Step
Printer and the renderer and the type of
holographic pixels that we devised and
imaged
you can see a direct correlation to a
real-time holographic display
and feature sizes of some of these
devices are starting to get down to like
example um
space light modulated it's got and I can
get five Micron feature sizes on yes and
you can get that in a phase only mode
that gives you 2 pi
per cell rotation so that actually
starts to get pretty interesting lost me
on that one but that's okay but it's a
phase thing in other words you can get
enough phase think about why do we do
Holograms with lasers because we can't
record the phase of light yes we can
record its color we can record its
brightness but we can't record which
direction it's going
so holography has been stuck forever
with lasers because that's the only way
we've come up to record the phase of
light
but all light actually does have phase
maybe that's a new research Direction
how to record the phase of light
well in most cases
random phases I think well it's random
but it is coming from somewhere yes
yes there is facial information in that
beam of light that's bouncing off that
switch to my left
but uh so you know there's there's some
interesting directions and I think right
now what's going on with some of the
real-time 3D displays that are
diffractive in nature the University of
Arizona work that's going on with those
photorefacto polymers yes that can be
written too that's pretty exciting like
I said these little
um they're right now they're 10 24 by
1024 but they have five Micron feature
sizes and if you are willing to pay them
enough they'll give you one that's phase
only that's looking pretty interesting
so I think there's maybe a path to a
real-time holographic display that would
be wonderful because there's so many
competing Technologies now
you have to work a little harder maybe
to get something out of it but you know
there's uh what's that group that's
doing that thing where they're you know
do you remember a few years back there
was a woman from Stanford that had done
a little dope Cube little Crystal oh yes
scanning an infrared laser into it and
basically drawing you know X and Y
scanning into it and getting
fluorescence off of the molecules big
hit out of spie yes West a few years
back there were lines almost reminiscent
of one Emmett Leaf had his Holograms at
the optical Society of America
but but there's a group now and I will
have to I apologize for not having this
I just came across their um website
yesterday
and the Optics gosh darn it where is it
now but um they took that same idea
you've got a a little Cube it's two
centimeters by ten two centimeters but
it's kind of like filled with little
particles that will fluoresce with um
infrared illumination
so they're you know X and Y scanning you
know they're doing a little bit of what
like uh Mike Cali was doing at the media
lab which was kind of like doing
real-time renderings with slices so you
can couple that together and you have
this little two centimeter
if you give me one second I'm actually
dialing through my emails
and I will tell you the name of this
copy that's pretty exciting although
it's not it's not holographic it's
interesting
technology it's a scanner
and getting three-dimensional
fluorescing to go on so that's not all
the graphic in that sense
but they'll call it a hologram anyway
they will thank you CNN yes
I get so frustrated
when non-holography gets mistagged
it's very unfortunate but it happens
every day and it's
it's having an adverse effect on
holographic workshops and holographic
exhibit
because I've had the public come to
shows where they would look at the
Holograms on the wall and they would
turn around and say this is not what I
expected a hologram to be this is really
a good observation
because you know Star Wars which was
great in so many ways Princess Leia was
the bane of holography for a long time
because you would get calls well that's
what do you mean you can't do that Lucas
can do that yeah
and and so and the same thing has
happened with this and again why don't
and what's really too bad is why don't
they just call it what it was because it
really was good for what it was it's
kind of like tracking you know motion
capture for blue screen rendering
multiple view capture from blue screen
that's all they were doing
um oh 3D icon
okay
is they have a thing called c space
they're being honest they call it a true
volumetric display and that would be
correct
but I think you're right I think we all
want to see
the right
um
labeling of stuff so because holography
really does need this chance in the sun
again well you know
there's another way of looking at it and
that is who cares if holography doesn't
move beyond what it is
good enough for what it is as it is
and it may always be what it is and take
that as far as we can take it
um it is you're right I'm 100 agree with
you there is nothing wrong with what
holography can do today
um and see more of it out there I
recently gave a talk to the northeastern
Optical Society of America which was
kind of like a history my history of
water oh yes I saw that listed how did
that go and it went really well and the
key thing that tripped everybody that
came in was like there were 35 Holograms
up there along you know somewhere in my
books some were exhibit pieces that were
display Holograms they hadn't seen any
of this stuff close up for like 15 years
some of them had never seen them and
they were all these were all people that
were Optical Engineers around the Boston
area a few I heard had worked in
Polaroid the old days but none had been
from their holography group
um and they were just blown away they
were like wow these are really beautiful
this is really stunning why isn't
anybody do you used to do this why don't
you do this now yeah yeah and that
really got um
you know all the hairs in the back of my
head standing up again
it's going to have a Revival and it's
not going to have anything to do with
workstations
for hitting a print button
having a holographic RGB
that's all coming and it's all going to
be great if you haven't seen the print I
made from the Holo printer at MIT what
was the con car
that wasn't the Alcove hologram no no no
no this is in the same genre of work
that zebra does but oh I said left
before me and then we followed up with
that message I should um well if you
keep track of you know lasersmith a
larger Dash holography.com
lasersmith-holography.com these things
are going to get posted over the next
month or two GIF animations and jpeg
animations and I will make sure that we
have a link
because I'm gonna you know this then
you'll get a chance to see that it's a
full Parallax pool care uh color
hologram that was digitally printed with
the holder printer I built there that
has one half millimeter pixels
so I mean that's an option that's one of
them you're right Frank it's all of
these flavors of holography it's It's
one step reflection Holograms of
beautiful dioramas but always moving on
doesn't necessarily mean giving up the
old ways of doing things
I think a lot of people you know
soon drop the old way of doing
holography and
I want to try and keep the old
holography as a craft and still keep it
alive oh you're speaking to my heart
Springs yeah I loved I mean that's the
first part of my calling with this is it
is a craft for me and I don't have a
problem with that
is there anything that you'd like to
cover that we haven't had a chance to
talk since 40 minutes I'm not done doing
it I I've been so reinvigorated TJ's
been in touch he's like saying Steve you
got to come out to China this biography
concept that's a long ways I don't know
if I can get there but it may make it I
mean digging out those Holograms and
looking at this phenomena my wife said
to me laugh I said why are you know have
our tenant move out in the basement and
take it over and put a lab back together
and I've worked with so you know I I may
end up getting my heart strings pulled
again
um we'll see well if you're ever in the
Philadelphia
New York metropolitan area that triangle
right there I'm right in Allentown
Pennsylvania we'd love to have you as a
guest sometimes so stop in
oh it'd be good to see you and and in
you or if any of your listeners are ever
in the Boston area
give me a ring
have a few Holograms or uh got plenty
actually and a cup of coffee all right
Stephen thank you so much for being on
the show I should have this up
definitely by the end of the week and I
hope you get a lot of listeners and a
lot of people will be coming to your
website to check out your updates here
this is great now I got to get my rear
and gear and just add more pages all
right thanks for listening so much for
taking all the time Stephen
bye-bye